Guide to the George Charles Poppensiek papers, 1942-2013.
Poppensiek, George Charles papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Charles Poppensiek papers, 1942-2013.
24-2-2149
Poppensiek
18.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, printed material, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of George Charles Poppensiek as Professor of Comparative Medicine at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, Cornell University, especially relating to collaboration with institutes in other countries, and office records.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
George Charles Poppensiek (1918- ) received his V.M.D. (Latin spelling of D.V.M.) degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1942 and an M.S. from Cornell University in 1951. He taught at the University of Pennsylvania and the University of Maryland before working as a department head with the Lederle Laboratories Division of American Cyanamid Company where he was responsible for veterinary vaccine and antiserum production. In 1949 he came to Cornell to begin graduate studies in virology and pathology. From 1951 to 1955 he served as a research associate in the Veterinary Virus Research Institute at Cornell. From 1955 to 1958, he worked at the U.S.D. A.'s Plum Island Animal Disease Laboratory, working on highly infectious foreign animal diseases. In 1959 he returned to Cornell to become Dean of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, a position he held until 1974. He was then named as the James Law Professor of Comparative Medicine. He retired in 1988. From 1974 to 1988 he also was appointed to the staff of the Department of Preventative Medicine at the Upstate Medical Center in Syracuse as a Research Professor. He belonged to numerous veterinary organizations and served as a consultant to other universities and projects.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of George Charles Poppensiek as Professor of Comparative Medicine at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, Cornell University, especially relating to collaboration with institutes in other countries, and office records, except financial records, for the department.
Also personal files of Dean Poppensiek, including six scrapbooks with clippings, photographs, letters, and certificates, compiled by his wife Edith Marion Wallace Poppensiek, 1943-2006; files with articles, photographs, certificates, and miscellany, 1943-2000; commencement programs, 1942, 1952; writings by George Poppensiek on veterinary and popular topics; consultant's reports; annual reports and other historical publications relating to the College of Veterinary Medicine; and plaques and certificates honoring him. Also many self published writings on various science related subjects that he wrote for his family members to help teach them about the world and engage them in science.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Poppensiek, George C.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.Dean.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.Office of Comparative Medicine.
Subjects:
Medicine, Comparative--Study and teaching.; Veterinary medicine--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Any sensitive employee records or administrative files from time as Dean or with the Office of Comparative Medicine, including, but not limited to Box 13 Folders 1 & 2. Restricted to permission of office of origin.
SERIES LIST
Series I. General Files and Correspondence
Series II. Alpha File Correspondence
Series III. College of Veterinary Medicine, Mississippi State University
Series IV. Travel Reports
Series V. Material for friends and family, authored/collected by Poppensiek
Series VI. Scrapbooks, Certificates and Plaques
Series VII. Other Writings and Publications
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General Files
  - Food and Agriculture Act of 1977, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Vet. Medical Association (AVMA) Council on Biologic and Therapeutic Agents, 1975, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Rotary Club, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Samuel F. Scheidy, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Animal Diseases and Ectoparasites - National Academy of Sciences, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Northwest Regional Veterinary College, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Medical College - Cornell Veterinary College Collaborative Program, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - New Jersey Equine Project, 197-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - US Animal Health Association (USAHA) Committee on Morbidity and Mortality Reporting, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Morbidity and Mortality Symposium, Nashville, November 1982, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - USAHA Committee on Morbidity and Mortality Reporting Meeting, Nashville, 8 November 1982, October - November 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - USAHA Morbidity and Mortality, 1981, February - August 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Animal Disease Reporting System, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - XIX World Veterinary Congress, Mexico City, Mexico., 15 - 21 August 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - WHO: Expert Committee on Bacterial and Virus Diseases, Autumn 1981, Surveillance of Zoonoses, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Research - Regulatory Interrelationship Review Committee (I), April - September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research - Regulatory Interrelationship Review Committee (II), 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Students, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - National Veterinary Congress, Poland, September 21-23, 1978, October 1978- May 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Plum Island Animal Disease Center, December 1980 - May 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Plum Island Animal Disease Center Training Program Evaluation. May 1-9, 1980, December 1975 - April 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners (NBVME), July 1974 - January 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners (NBVME), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - National Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners (NBVME), 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - National Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners (NBVME), 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NAS/NRC Committee on Aquatic Health, 1969, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Animal Health, Washington D.C., December 8-9, 1977, November 1977 - January 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chapter for Book on Virus Diseases (J. J. Callis), December 1978 - July 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Convocation Ceremonies, Veterinary Medicine, University of Missouri, May 13 1978, February 1978 - June 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Review of Performance, Department of Microbiology, College of Veterinary Medicine, March 1978 - May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July 1977 - August 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board On Agricultural and Renewable Resources, Meeting of June 19-20, 1978, Estses Park, Colorado, December 1977 - July 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Committees on Animal Health and Animal Nutrition, Washington D.C., March 8-9, 1979, January 1979 - June 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Animal Health, April 27-28, 1978, Washington D.C., March 1978 - May 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Animal Health NAS/NRC, Washington D.C., October 16-17, 1978, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Animal Health Committee Meeting, October 16-17, June 1979 - September 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Meeting of Committee on Animal Health, October 16-17, 1979, June 1979 - January 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Meeting on Committee on Animal Health and Committee on Animal Nutrition, March 4-6, 1980, December 1979 - March 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence NAS/NRC, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - NAS Committee on Animal Health, April 1979 - January 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Dr. F. Brian Leech, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Study on Risks of Foreign Animal Diseases NAS/NRC, November 1979 - December 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Veterinary Public Health, January 1979 - April 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - BARD Research Project Proposal, Reviews, Animal Protection, 1983, September 1982 - September 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Operations Crossroads Africa Inc., June 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bureau of Veterinary Medicine (BVM), Food and Drug Administration (FDA), October 1977, May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Antibiotics, Animal Feed, BVM FDA, May 1976 - December 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - FDA; MON's, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Evaluation of Teaching Infectious Diseases; Feb/March, 1981, University of Florida, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), December 1975 - May 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - American Academy of Microbiology, April 1970 - February 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - American Board of Medical Microbiology, November 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - American College of Veterinary Microbiologists, February 1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - American College of Theriogenologists, March 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - National Committee to Save Our Schools of Health, March 1971 - July 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Animal Repellent Testing, February 1979 - March 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Universidad Nacional De La Plata, October 1978 - February 1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - New Jersey Equine Project, March 1969 - October 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - USAHA Committee on Foreign Animal Diseases, May 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - USAHA: Morbidity and Mortality Committee, October 1981 Meeting, February 1960 - December 1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Ohio State Pharmacokinetic Study, BVM, FDA, April 1977 - June 1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - United Way 1982, March 1982 - September 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tuskegee Institute School of veterinary Medicine - Financial Evaluation 1979, January 1979 - May 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Louisiana State University School of Veterinary Medicine - Program Evaluation, February 1977 - May 1980 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - BID Mission to Argentina, Virology and Fish Technology, (PIPECA), 1977 (I), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - BID Mission to Argentina, Virology and Fish Technology, (PIPECA), 1977 (II), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Melby, J. C., April 1975 - October 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Merieux Institute, France, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Microbiology Search Committee, June 1983 - January 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mulhern, F. J., 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Moulton, Dr. W. M., October 1977 - February 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minnesota VMA, July 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences Nominations, October 1982 - June 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences CAH, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - NAS/NRC, 1968-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners, AVMA, August 1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - National Institutes of Health, February 1983, February 1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - North East Regional Council, May 1981 - August 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - North East Regional Council, November 1982 - December 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ad Hoc Regional Council, Joint Council on Food and Agricultural Sciences, July 1979 - September 1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Gil Porter, February 1980 - October 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - N. Y. S. College of Veterinary Medicine Teaching Hospital Procedure and Policy Manual, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - N. Y. S. Veterinary Medicine Society, August 1982 - August 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Darien Gap Foot and Mouth Disease Problem II, January 1977 - June 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pan American Highway Environmental Impact Statement, January 1976 - July 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pan American Health Organization, January 1981 - February 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pathology Department, Veterinary College, October 1974 - October 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Class Reunion, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, May 21, 1977, December 1983 - April 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Publications, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Plum Island Animal Disease Center, September 1976 - December 1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Personal, Poppensiek, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Includes photographs, newsprint, articles etc.
  - Preventive Medicine Search Committee (I), June 1985 - August 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Preventive Medicine Search Committee (II), July 1985 - November 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Report of the N. Y. S. Veterinary College, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - November 1983 Programs, Rotary Club of Ithaca, October 1983 - December 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sabbatical Leave - Explorations, December 1984 - February 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, February 1975 - February 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Regional Educational Program for Animal Health Assistants (REPEHA), June 1982 - August 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Walls, Earl, December 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Research Proposals, May 1981 - June 1981 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Research Advisory Committee, January 1983 - May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Research Advisory Committee, Review, February 1983 - March 1983 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Research Advisory Meeting, 9-13 January, 1983, January 1983 - May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - BARD, February 1979 - April 1981 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - BARD, Peer Reviewers Comments, April 1981 - August 1985 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Addresses, 1954-1974 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Reprints and Publications, 1948-1984 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Addresses, May 1959, January 1964 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Personal: Visiting Cards etc., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Trinidad; May 17-22, 1981, May 1979 - April 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Trinidad/Tobago; May 17-22, 1981, January 1981 - May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Trinidad, October 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Calmaquip Equipment, May 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Trinidad Equipment, July 1979 - January 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Articles sent to others, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Amoroso, Amanuel C., February 1979 - November 1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Moe, Vincent G., June 1978 - March 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - McCormick, E. Phillip, October 1979 - February 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Picou, David, December 1978 - June 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (I), June 1978 - August 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (II), April 1978 - September 1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, March 1978 - January 1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Floor Plans, April 1979 - December 1980 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, Trinidad, April 1979 - December 1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Memo's for the Record, January 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Info, March 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, Trinidad, August 1973 - August 1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Appointment, Consultant, Trinidad, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Includes copies of religious texts by William Branham and Peary Green
  - Miscellaneous, Trinidad, 1964-1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, Trinidad: Articles and Reprints, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Trinidad Report (PAHO), Volume I, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Trinidad Report (PAHO), Volume II, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Wetterberg Foundation, July 1981 - March 1984 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Africa: Origin of the Name, April 1980 - October 1980 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, January 1976 - July 1979 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - USAHA, NADDS, March 1983 - August 1983 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - USAHA, NADDS, November 1982 - March 1983 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - USAHA, NADDS, Roger S. Morris Information, November 1982 - December 1982 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Walnut Pruning and Propagation, 1977-1978, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    Includes photographs.
  - Walnut Toxicity Corres, September 1977 - October 1984 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Copies of Manning Correspondence, May 1980 - August 1984 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Walnut Toxicity Seminar, 19 February 1981, 1934, September 1976 - April 1983 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Requests for Walnut Toxicity Perspective, April 1983 - July 1983 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Walnut Toxicity Material, July 1977 - May 1984 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Walnut Toxicity Not LHM, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Walnut Toxicity Reprints, 8-56 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Perspective Paper 1982 and Correspondence, August 1982 - September 1983 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Walnut Toxicity General, Miscellaneous, November 1976 - November 1984 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Walnut Toxicity Vet Papers, October 1982 - August 1983 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Walnut Toxicity Notes and Summary 1982, August 1981 - 1982 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Personal Papers (I), 1952-1973 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Personal Papers (II), 1959-1979 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Walnut Toxicity Material, June 1982 - May 1984 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Manning Correspondence - Originals, May 1980 - August 1984 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Leonard Krook, September 1982 - May 1984 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - American Board of Medical Microbiology, August 1980 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Anderson, R K, July 1983 - December 1983 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Association of American Veterinary Medical Colleges, 1977-1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Inter-Americanism Development Bank, Mission to Argentina, 1-17 September 1977, August 1977 - September 1977 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - American Society of Virology, August 1982 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association, January 1976 - January 1984 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association, August 1971 - January 1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Annual Report, 1980, December 1977 - December 1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Argentina, National Academy of Agronomy and Veterinary Medicine, December 1980 - December 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Review of the Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Arizona, November 1983 - April 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - VI International Meeting on Veterinary Science, La Plata University, Argentina, 5 - 11 November 1978, September 1978 - March 1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Letters, 1966-1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Beal, Dr. Victor C., December 1978 - April 1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Budget Documents, Historical, 1972-1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Columbia Aftosa Research project, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Veterinarian, Inc., September 1976 - April 1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University Medical College, New York City, January 1983 - February 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Dedication - Multicategorical Research Building, January 1974 - June 1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Mesones, de Pedro, July 1980 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Colloquium on Diarrhoeal Diseases, January 1978 - September 1978 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Faculty and Professional Staff, N. Y. S. College of Veterinary Medicine, 1977, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization, 1978-1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Food and Drug Administration, September 1981 - October 1982 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Federal Trade Commission, December 1975 - February 1976 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Feldman, Dr. Harry A., 1974-1980 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Journal of Infection and Immunity, November 1972 - June 1973 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - International Agriculture Development Service, January 1976 - March 1977 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - International Agriculture, June 1983 - April 1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Council of Intersociety Presidents, May 1979 - June 1979 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Kimron Institute, Israel, August 1980 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Laboratory Fee, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Veterinary Manpower, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Maurer, Fred D., January 1975 - June 1976 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - McEntee, Kenneth, October 1975 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Registry - Veterinary Reproductive Pathology, McEntee, January 1977 - November 1979 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Registry - Veterinary Reproductive Pathology, McEntee, January 1977 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - NADDS NAHMS (I), January 1985 - November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - NADDS NAHMS (II), July 1985 - January 1986 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - NADS, August 1983 - November 1984 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - NADS Correspondence, November 1983 - August 1984 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Speeches and Papers (I), 1960-1981 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Speeches and papers (II), 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - USAHA Committee on Animal Disease Surveillance, Old Morbidity and Mortality Reports, August 1983 - November 1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - USAHA Morbidity and Mortality: New Members Requests and Responses, November 1981 - April 1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - USAHA Morbidity and Mortality Committee, April 1981 - July 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - USAHA NADDS NAHMS, February 1985 - December 1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - USDA; APHIS; NADS; National Animal Disease Surveillance, August 1983 - February 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Beal, Victor C., June 1981 - January 1982 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - History, Veterinary Microbiology, September 1982 - July 1983 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Haynes, Dr. N. C. Bruce, April 1979 - August 1979 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Haiti, July 1961 - January 1973 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    Includes photographs
  - Goals, Veterinary College, 1961, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - IICA (Inter-American Institute for Cooperation on Agriculture): Memorandums for the Record, August 1976 - June 1982 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - IICA: "Overview" Perspective (Draft), December 1981 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - IICA: Miscellaneous Documents, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - IICA: Miscellaneous Correspondence, October 1981 - September 1986 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - IICA: Original Working Document, February 1982, June 1979 - March 1982 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - IICA Working Document (II), April 1982 - June 1983 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - IICA: Animal Health Program (I), November 1979 - February 1980 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - IICA: Animal Health Program (II), March 1979 - February 1982 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Wetterberg Foundation, October 1992 - November 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    RESTRICTED
  - Recommendation Letters, 1976-1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Research Tower Dedication, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Speeches and Papers, 1959-1971 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Speeches and Papers, 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Speeches and Papers, 1980-1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: republications, 1989 - 1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Simon and Schuster Dictionary, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - IA300, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Swienzynski, 1967-1988 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Trinidad, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Tuskegee University ,Frederick Douglas Patterson, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - IICA Meeting, Mexico 19-23 September 1983, June 1983 - September 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Immunity to Selected Equine Infectious Diseases Meeting, 19-21 November, 1968, University of Kentucky, Jun 1968 - November 1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - International; Laboratory for Research on Animal Diseases, July 1978 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - International Programs, Dean, February 1984 - June 1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - International Veterinary Medicine, July 1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Kita, Dr. Jerzy, December 1964 - March 1980 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - NADDS, April 1981 - May 1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - National Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners: PES Reclassification, August 1978 - February 1979 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1973, 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Northeast Regional Council, Joint Council on Food and Agricultural Sciences, July 1986 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Office International Des Epizooties, 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - VM 519 Cocal Virus, March 1979 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Collagen, Dr. A. L. Rubin, September 1973 - October 1973 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Veterinary School Faculty Profiles, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Program: 67th Annual Conference for Veterinarians, N. Y. S. Veterinary College; "Don't forget the Horse Doctor": The first forty years of one of the first veterinary colleges in America, January 1975 (Box 16, Folder 15)